Guide to the William Blathwayt Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1646-1796; Series I; 4.0' (10 boxes)
  - Lowndes, William, 1652-1724
    - LS to Charles Fox and William Blathwayt, Treasury Chambers, 1703 Nov 12
      Writing on behalf of the Lord Treasurer to ask them to report on the enclosed memorial concerning respites in Lord Portmore's regiment. The memorial is certified by Adam Cardonnel and is accompanied by a certificate by Portmore. Cf. Cal. Treas. Books, XVIII, p. 450. 1. Fox, Charles, d. 1713. 2. Great Britain. Army. I. Godolphin, Sidney Godolphin, 1st Earl of, 1645-1712. II. Cardonnel, Adam, d. 1719: certification of memorial, 1703 Nov 9. III. Portmore, David Colyear, 1st Earl of, d. 1730.
  - Lucas, Robert Lucas, 3rd Baron, d. 1705
    - 3 ALS to [William Blathwayt], Tower of London, 1694 Aug 14-31 (Box 6, Folder 120)
      Reporting the escape of and search for Colonel Parker, who was implicated in a plot against the king. 1. Parker, John, fl. 1676-1705.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], Tower of London, 1694 Oct 26
      Reporting the escape of Lord Clancarty from the Tower through negligence of his warden. 1. Clancarty, Donough Maccarthy, 4th Earl of, 1668-1734.
  - Lyttelton, Charles, 2nd Bart., 1629-1716
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], London, 1698 Aug 23
      Need for a new fort major for Shereness and new arms for his regiment. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Macarty, Charles
    - 1 ALS and 1 LS to William Blathwayt, Guernsey, 1686 Sep 12 (Box 6, Folder 121)
      - Reporting increasing disaffection to, 1687 Jun 11
      - the crown on Guernsey. 1. Guernsey--History.
  - Mackworth, Humphrey, Sir, 1657-1727
    - Letter, copy, to Sir Charles Hedges, n.p., 1701 Aug 21
      Enclosing a treatise (presumably his A Vindication of the rights of the Commons of England ) for the King. The book with this copy of the letter was sent to Blathwayt by Hedges on 22 August. 1. Hedges, Charles, Sir, d. 1714.
  - Magennis of Iveagh, Bryan Magennis, 5th Viscount, d. 1692
    - ALS to Sir Paul Rycaut, Tropaw, 1692 Aug 13/23
      Relating the general disappointment of the Irish soldiers serving the Emperor. 1. Rycaut, Paul, Sir, 1628-1700. 2. Great Britain. Army.
  - Manchester, Charles Montague, first Duke of, 1660?-1722
    - Memoir concerning the Protestants at La Rochelle: contemporary ms. copy, [1700?] (Box 6, Folder 122)
      1. Huguenots--France. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations--France.
  - Mansell, William, 7th bart., 1670-1732
    - 2 ALS to William Blathwayt, Plymouth, 1702 Aug 12, 25
      Reporting the condition of his regiment and urging that his subsistence be paid. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Marlborough, John Churchill, 1st Duke of, 1650-1722
    - Letter (copy, in French) to the States General, Camp at Heleseren, 1702 Aug 26
      Reporting the progress in his campaign. Accompanied by a copy of the reply by the States General, 1702 Aug 28. 1. Netherlands (United Provinces, 1581-1795) Staten generaal. 2. Spanish Succession, War of the, 1701-1714.
  - Martyn, Thomas
    - 3 ALS to William Blathwayt, Port Royal, 1680 Nov 10- (Box 6, Folder 123)
      - Acknowledging Blathwayt's appointment, 1680/81 Mar 22
      - as Surveyor and Auditor General of Jamaica; urging him not to trust Capt. Francis Mingham; reporting on accounts. 1. Mingham, Francis. 3. Jamaica-- History.
    - ALS to the Treasury Lords, [Port Royal], 1680 Nov 11
      Acknowledging Blathwayt's appointment as Surveyor and Auditor General of Jamaica and reporting the confused state of finances in Jamaica despite the efforts of Governors Vaughan and Carlisle and of Sir Henry Morgan. 1. Great Britain. Treasury. 2. Morgan, Henry, Sir, 1635?-1688. 3. Carbery, John Vaughan, 3rd Earl of, 1640-1713. 4. Carlisle, Charles Howard, 1st Earl of, 1629-1685. 5. Jamaica--History.
  - Mathews, William
    - ALS to Mr. Thurston, Spithead, 1704 Aug 10
      "Sr. We Embarked on the 8th inst & had writ to you then had I been able..." 1. Thurston, Mr.
  - May, Humphrey, d. 1722
    - Letter (copy) to unidentified recipient, Dublin Castle, 1698 Aug 27 (Box 6, Folder 124)
      Reporting the arrival in Dublin of troops from Flanders. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Memorials
    - "Memoire pour le Roy touchant le Psautier francois", [ca. 1695]
      Concerning a new translation of the Psalms for the use of Huguenots. 1. Great Britain. Sovereigns, etc., 1694-1702 (William III). 2. Huguenots --France. 3. Bible. French. O.T. Psalms.
    - "Memorial of the Spanish Ambassador to the States": contemporary ms. copy (in French), The Hague, 1693 Oct 7
      - Discussing the role of Spain in the War of the Grand Alliance. 1. Spain--Foreign relations-- Netherlands. 2. Grand Alliance. War of the, 1689-1697.
        See: Oversize, Box 12, folder 240
  - Minshull, Robert
    - ALS to John Thurston, Liverpool, 1702 Jul 12 (Box 6, Folder 125)
      Requesting that his wish for change of quarters be shown to Blathwayt. 1. Thurston, John, d. 1732. 2. Great Britain. Army.
  - Moeringh, Dutch envoy
    - Letter (copy, in Dutch) to unnamed recipient, Copenhagen, 1683 May 5/15
      Concerning affairs in Denmark. 1. Netherlands--Foreign relations-- Denmark.
  - Montagu, Ralph Montagu, 1st Duke of, 1638?-1709
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], London, 1694 Jul 17
      Expresses his need for the King's signature for a Treasury warrant assigning him £1300 from Lord Preston's attainted estate. 1. Great Britain. Treasury. 2. Preston, Richard Graham, Viscount, 1648-1695.
  - Montauban, St. F. de Chevrièves
    - 2 ALS to William Blathwayt, Coni and Turin, 1693 Oct 24 (Box 6, Folder 126)
      - Asking to be made colonel of a, Dec 9
      - regiment, the first vacancy caused by the death of the Duke of Schomberg and the second by Col. Mombrun. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Schomberg, Charles Schomberg, 2nd Duke of, 1645- 1693.
  - Montigori, Mons. de
    - ALS (in French) to [William Blathwayt?], Au Camp, 1695 Sep 20
      Montigori was one of the French Reformed officers in British pay. 1. Great Britain. Army. French Reformed Officers.
  - Mountcashell, Justin Maccarty, Viscount, d. 1694.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], Chester, 1686 Jun 26
      Complaining about the ignorance of the Governor of Chester (Peter Shakerley). 1. Shakerley, Peter. 2. Chester, Eng.
  - Mountjoy, William Stewart, 2nd Viscount, d. 1733
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], London, 1694 Jun 26 (Box 6, Folder 127)
      Concerning a dispute over pay based on the date of commissions. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Münster (Diocese)
    - "A paper Concerning a most inhumane attempt...undertaken...upon the person, & state of the Bishop of Munster": contemporary ms. copy., [ca. 1690]
  - Myddelton, Charles
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], Liege, 1695 Sep 20
      About providing assistance to the soldiers. Endorsed by Blathwayt "From Father Middleton." 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Netherlands. Navy
    - "Petition of those concerned in the Dutch Transport Ships": contemporary ms. copy (in Dutch), [after 1694] (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Netherlands (United provinces, 1581-1795). [Staten generaal]
    - Extract of minutes of an Estates General meeting: contemporary ms. copy (in Dutch), 1693 Jul 23
      Concerning English and Dutch negotiations with the Ottoman Empire; endorsed "Secret". 1. Netherlands--Foreign relations-- Turkey. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Turkey.
  - Neville Family
    - "The Descent of the Earls of Warwick and Salisbury...": anon. ms., [ca. 1680]
      The family tree is traced from the first Earl of Westmoreland to the time of Edward V. 1. Genealogy.
  - Newsletters
    - 4 newsletters (in Dutch and French), Westminster, 1682 Oct 6- (Box 6, Folder 129)
      - Newsletters written by one Van, 1682/3 Jan 8
      - Beuninger for the Dutch about English affairs. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Netherlands. I. Van Beuninger, Mr.
    - Collection of 11 newsletters (in French) concerning activities in the Savoy, Milan, 1697 Jul-Oct
      Endorsed by William Blathwayt.
    - Newsletter, Cadiz, 1698 Aug 21 (Box 6, Folder 130)
      Reporting ship movements in Cadiz; endorsed by Blathwayt.
    - Newsletter, Paris, 1698 Aug 25
      Reporting the arrival of the Dutch Ambassadors in Paris; (in French) 1. Netherlands--Foreign relations-- France.
    - Newsletter, Dublin, 1698 Oct 6
      Reporting votes in the Irish Parliament. Endorsed by Blathwayt. 1. Ireland, Parliament, 1698.
    - Newsletter, [Switzerland], 1698 Oct 17
      Printed newspaper about Swiss affairs.
    - 3 newsletters, reporting news from military camps in Italy, 1702 Apr-Jul (Box 6, Folder 131)
      News of Naples, Rome, Pisa, Leghorn, and Florence. 1. Great Britain. Army.
    - 6 newsletters, reporting news from military camps in Flanders., 1702-05
  - Norff, Mons.
    - 2 ALS to [William Blathwayt], The Hague, 1702 Apr 7 (Box 6, Folder 132)
      - Writing as envoy from Münster to, May 23
      - offer condolences on the King's death and to seek aid to identify a soldier with the English forces in Jamaica. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Münster.
  - Norfolk, Henry Howard, 7th Duke of, 1655-1701
    - ALS to William III, n.p., 1694 Sep 28/
      - Asking that his brother-in-law, the, Oct 8
      - Duke of Gordon, be released from confinement on account of his ill health. 1. Gordon, George Gordon, 1st Duke of, 1649-1716.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], n.p., 1694 Sep 28/
      - Enclosing a letter of T. Spencer to, Oct 8
      - the Duchess of Gordon, 1694 Jul 12, about the Duke of Gordon's health, which he wishes shown to the king. 1. Gordon, Elizabeth Howard, Duchess of, d. 1732. 2. Gordon, George Gordon, 1st Duke of, 1649-1716. I. Spencer, T.
  - Nuremberg. Law, Statutes, etc.
    - "Extractus Protocolli": contemporary ms. copy (in German), Nuremberg, 1693 Mar 18/28
      About a meeting in Nuremberg.
  - O'Donnell, Hugh Balldearg, d. 1704
    - ALS to Lord Galway, [1694] (Box 6, Folder 133)
      Expressing his fears that the Queen's death and the King's absence might lead to disaffection in England and Ireland, and offering to return to England to ferret out such plans. 1. Ruvigny and Raineval, Henri de Massue de Ruvigny, 2nd Marquis of, 1648-1720.
  - Ogle, Thomas
    - ALS to Samuel Lynn, n.p., [1702 Aug 27]
      Asks about a route for Captain Astley's additional company to Sir Bevill Granville's late regiment in Holland.
  - Orford, Margaret (Rolle) Walpole, Countess of, 1709-1781
    - Last Will and Testament: contemporary ms. copy, Florence, 1781 Jan 19
      A description of the opening of her will, with a copy of the certificate of her death. The entire account was certified by Sir Horace Mann. 1. Mann, Horace, 1st bart. 1701- 1786.
  - Ormonde, James Butler, 1st Duke of, 1610-1688
    - "The State of the Case concerning the Course Lands of Kerry, Between the Duke of Ormonde, Robt. Marshall & McGillicuddy of ye 3 Regiments": anon. ms. (Box 6, Folder 134)
      I. Marshall, Robert.
  - Orth, Edward, d. 1698
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Hamburg, 1694 Oct 23
      Forwarding letters for Hugh Greg. Orth was Rycaut's secretary. 1. Greg, Hugh, d. 1702.
  - Osuna, Gaspar Tellex Girón, 5. duque de, 1625-1694
    - Letter (copy) to the Pope, [ca. 1685]
      1. Catholic Church. Pope, 1676-1689. (Innocentius XI).
  - Paget, William Paget, 6th Baron, 1637-1713
    - 1 ALS and 1 letter (copy) to [William Blathwayt], Adrianople and Pera, 1693 Jun 8/18 (Box 6, Folder 135)
      - Writing as English Ambassador in, Oct 10/20
      - Turkey on diplomatic matters. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Turkey.
    - LS to Robert Sutton, Adrianople, 1698 May 9
      Concerning negotiations which led to the Treaty of Carlowitz. 1. Sutton, Robert, 1671-1746. 2. Carlowitz, Peace of, 1699.
    - Bill for Extraordinary Expenses: holograph ms., Adrianople, 1698 Jun 10
    - 2 ALS to [William Blathwayt], Kayali and the Ottoman camp near Sophia, 1698 Jun 19 (Box 6, Folder 136)
      - Reporting his efforts and expenses, Jul 14/24
      - in his role as mediator between the Holy Roman and Ottoman Empires. Accompanied by the "Answer of ye Grand Vegir to my Lord Pagett upon his going to the Place of Congress". 1698 [Jun?], 2 pp. (in Italian). 1. Turkey, Sovereigns, 1695-1703 (Mustafa II).
    - 8 letters (extracts) to unnamed recipients, near Belgrade, Carlowitz, and Vienna, 1698 Oct 6-
      - Describing the final negotiations, Dec 13
      - leading to the Peace of Carlowitz. Accompanied by copies of several of the articles. 1. Carlowitz, Peace of, 1699. 2. Turkey Treaties, etc., 1695-1703 (Mustafa II).
  - Paisecoeur, Pierre
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Rotterdam, 1695 Aug 13 (Box 6, Folder 137)
      About Blathwayt's order of whiskey.
  - Peter I, The Great, Emperor of Russia, 1672-1725
    - Letter (copy) translated from the Dutch, to William III, [The Hague], [1699]
      Concerning free trade between Russia and England; accompanied by William's reply, announcing that he has made Charles Goodfellow his Consul in Moscow. 1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Russia. 3. Great Britain--Commerce--Russia.
  - Petty, William, Sir, 1623-1687
    - "The Case between FitzGerald of Tecroghan, & W P ...", n.p., 1686 Jun 7
      Concerning lands in Ireland. The date is from Blathwayt's docket of receipt. 1. FitzGerald of Tecroghan, family.
  - Picke, Robert
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Newton, 1702 Jul 20 (Box 6, Folder 138)
      Acknowledging orders for marching to quarters. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Plowman, Mathew
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, New York, 1689 Jun 11
      Reporting the disastrous effect of the recent rebellion on the finances of New York; William and Mary cannot be proclaimed until the letters are forwarded from Boston. Plowman was the Collector and Receiver of New York. 1. New York (State)--History-- Colonial period, ca. 1600-1755.
  - Poland. Sovereigns, 1697-1733 (Augustus II)
    - Letter (copy, in Latin) to Lord Paget, Leopolis, 1698 Sep 5
      Concerning Paget's role as mediator in the Carlowitz negotiations. Accompanied by a letter, copy, from the Polish ambassador to Lord Paget, 1698 Oct 17. 1. Paget, William Paget, 6th Baron, 1637-1717. 2. Malchousky, Stanislaus. 3. Carlowitz, Peace of, 1699.
  - Poley, Edmund, 1655-1714
    - 17 ALS to William Blathwayt, Turin, 1692 Apr 5- (Box 6, Folder 139)
      - Writing as envoy extraordinary to the, May 21/31
      - Court of Savoy about military preparations against the French, his need of payment in order to afford an audience, and his efforts to raise money for the Duke of Schomberg and three French Reformed regiments. Accompanied by a copy of his letter to the Marquis of St. Thomas, 1692 May 30, the first minister to the Duke. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Savoy. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Schomberg, Charles Schomberg, 2nd Duke of, 1645-1693. 4. St. Thomas, Marquis de. 5. Victor Amadeus I, King of Sardinia, 1666-1732. 6. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
    - 9 ALS to William Blathwayt, Turin, 1692 Jun 3-18/28 (Box 6, Folder 140)
      Reporting allied preparations in the campaign in support of the Vaudois against the French and the drawn-out negotiations to get an edict for the re-establishment of the Vaudois. Accompanied by Poley's memorial to the Duke of Savoy, 1692 Jun 4, and his letter to the Marquis de St. Thomas, 1692 Jun 19. Enclosed in the letter of Jun 3 are answers of the Marquis de St. Thomas to Poley's memorial of May 26 and other letters. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Savoy. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. St. Thomas, Marquis de. 4. Victor Amadeus I, King of Sardinia, 1666 1732. 5. Waldenses--Piedmont. 6. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689- 1697.
    - 10 ALS to William Blathwayt, Turin, 1692 Jul 1-29
      Reporting the irresolution of the Court of Savoy in pressing the military campaign against the French and in publishing the edict for the re-establishment of the Vaudois. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Savoy. 2. Waldenses--Piedmont. 3. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689- 1697.
    - 11 ALS to William Blathwayt, Turin, 1692 Aug 2-30 (Box 6, Folder 141)
      Reporting the advance of the allied troops, including Schomberg's regiment, into France. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Schomberg, Charles Schomberg, 2nd Duke of, 1645- 1693. 3. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
    - 16 ALS to William Blathwayt, Turin, 1692 Sep 2-
      - Sending news of military engagements, Nov 4
      - involving allied troops and of their retreat to winter quarters, and insisting that his offer to resign his post be presented to the King without prior reference to Lord Nottingham. Accompanied by a project of the defensive alliance between the Duke of Savoy and the Protestant Cantons, agreed at Baden 1690 Jun 3, by the project of an edict to be published for the re-establishment of the Vaudois, and by a schedule of pay for the Duke of Savoy's army. 1. Nottingham, Daniel Finch, 2nd Earl of, 1647-1730. 2. Great Britain. Army. 3. Savoy (Duchy) Treaties, etc., 1675-1730 (Victor Amadeus I). 4. Waldenses--Piedmont. 5. Victor Amadeus I, King of Sardinia, 1666- 1732.
    - 16 ALS to William Blathwayt, Turin, 1693 Apr 1/11- (Box 6, Folder 142)
      - Sending news of allied military, Jun 6
      - preparations during his last two months before being recalled as Envoy to the Court of Savoy. His last audience with the Duke of Savoy took place on 1693 Jun 4. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Savoy. 2. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
    - Memorandum of cipher used by Poley in his diplomatic correspondence: contemporary ms. (copy), [1692]
      1. Ciphers.
  - Popple, William
    - 2 LS to William Blathwayt, Whitehall, 1697 Jul 9 (Box 7, Folder 143)
      Reports on the proceedings of the Council of Trade. Instructions for the government of Bermuda dispatched; Wool manufacture in Spain; number and pay of the men of war that attend the islands decided; receipt of papers from Maryland including complaints about the harboring of pirates in Pennsylvania; schemes for the employment of the poor and the Poor Rates; expediency of disbanding the soldiers in Jamaica; Mr. Chidley Brook's petition; letters to and from the American colonies; the question of the government of Bermuda. 1. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations. 2. Great Britain. Lords Justices.
  - Porter, Charles, Sir, 1631-1696
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Dublin, 1694 Jun 17
      Reporting news.
  - Portlock, Benjamin
    - Memorandum for William Blathwayt, n.p., [1692 Aug 7]
      The Duke of Ormonde thinks additional segments should be ordered for the detachment of guards going to sea. Portlock was Ormonde's secretary. 1. Great Britain. Army. I. Ormonde, James Butler, 2nd Duke of, 1655-1745.
  - Povey, John, d. 1705
    - ALS (draft) to Mr. Walls, Whitehall, 1691 Apr 11
      Warning him on behalf of Blathwayt to include merchant ships as well as men of war in the Downs on his list sent to the Plantation office. 1. Walls, Mr. 2. Great Britain. Board of Trade and Plantations.
  - Prez, Lord des
    - ALS (in French) to William III, Camp de Genappe, 1692 Jul 23 (Box 7, Folder 144)
      Writing on behalf of the Prince-Bishop of Liege for a further subsidy. 1. William III, King of Great Britain, 1650-1702. 2. Great Britain--Foreign relations--Liege.
  - Prior, Matthew, 1664-1721
    - 2 AL to [William Blathwayt], The Hague, 1695 Jun 26/
      - Enclosing "the last Edition of the, Jul 6
      - present State of France, which I, Jul 10/20
      - received last post from Paris by the Means of Detrevil our honest French Gazettier," and sending news. Both letters are damaged with serious loss of text.
  - Purcell, J. R.
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], Hull, 1687 Oct 5
      "...we finde a greate deal of alteration betweene this and York for our men are mightily throng'd here..." 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Queensberry, James Douglas, 2nd Duke of, 1662-1711
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, London, 1694 May 29 (Box 7, Folder 145)
      Wishing a warrant for £705 for clothing the Trumpets and Kettle Drum of the Troop of Scots guards. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Ramsay, George
    - 2 ALS to William Blathwayt, Brûges, 1696 Oct 17 (Box 7, Folder 146)
      - Concerning orders to the Scots, Dec 10
      - Regiments.
  - Ranelagh, Richard Jones
    - Letter, copy, to [the Lords Justices?, n.p.], [1691?]
      Concerning the payment of the regiments of Monmouth and Col. Luttrells.
  - Rawdon, Marmaduke
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, 1702 Oct 16
      Requesting orders for a route to quarters. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Relation
    - "Relation de l'arrivée de S. A. Royale aux Eaux de St. Maurice", [ca. 1695] (Box 7, Folder 147)
      1. Victor Amadeus I, King of Sardinia, 1666-1732.
    - "Relation d'une Conference tenue a Vienne a l'hostel d'Espagne": contemporary ms. copy, (in French), Vienna, 1695 Feb 8
      Concerning preparations for the Peace of Stockholm; Lexington was the English envoy at the meeting. 1. Lexington, Robert Sutton, 2nd Baron, 1661-1723. 2. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
  - Robinson, John, Bishop of London, 1650-1723
    - Letter (copy) to William Blathwayt, Stockholm, 1701 Jul 20 (Box 7, Folder 148)
      Describing a conference in Stockholm. 1. Great Britain--Foreign relations-- Sweden.
    - Letter (copy) to Lord Lexington, [Stockholm?], 1697 Jul 21
      Concerning relations between the Empire and Sweden. 1. Lexington, Robert Sutton, 2nd Baron, 1661-1723. 2. Holy Roman Empire--Foreign relations--Sweden.
  - Robinson, W.
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Chester, 1689 Dec 18
      Concerning provisions for Chester. Robinson was later made a commisary- general for the army. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Rochester, Laurence Hyde, 1st Earl of, 1641-1711
    - ALS to [William Blathwayt], n.p., [1702] (Box 7, Folder 149)
      Writing on behalf of Col. Gibson to procure the Queen's order for filling his regiment for service in Ireland. 1. Gibson, John, Sir, 1637-1717. 2. Great Britain. Army.
  - Roe, William
    - ALS to William Blathwayt, Portsmouth, 1702 Nov 20
      Request that his company leave Portsmouth for Plymouth by sea instead of by land, contrary to previous orders received by Col. Gibson. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Gibson, John, Sir, 1637-1717.
  - Romer, Wolfgang William, 1640-1713
    - AL (in French) to William Blathwayt, [1694/5 Feb 11]
      Concerning his pay as a colonel in the British army. 1. Great Britain. Army.
  - Romney, Henry Sidney, Earl of, 1641-1704
    - ALS to [Earl Conway], 1681 May 13 (Box 7, Folder 150)
      Excuses himself for not having attended some meeting. Reports on the travels of the Prince and Princess of Orange.
    - Letter (copy) to the Lords of the Admiralty, At the Camp at St. Gerard, 1691 Aug 18/28
      About Sieur Paul Bauwens, a subject of Spain and merchant, whose ship was taken by English privateers. Cf. C.S.P.D., 1690-1691, p. 494. 1. Great Britain. Admiralty.
  - Rooke, George, Sir, 1650-1709
    - Letter (copy, in French) to Count Guldenlew, a bord du Shrowsbury, 1700 Jul 10
      Concerning the aid Guldenlew can bring to achieving peace. Guldenlew was an Admiral of Denmark. 1. Guldenlew, Count. 2. Great Britain. Navy.
  - Ruvigny and Raineval, Henri de Massue de Ruvigny, 2nd Marquis of, 1648-1720
    - 11 ALS (in French) to William Blathwayt, Turin, 1694 Mar 23- (Box 7, Folder 151)
      - Writing as English Envoy in Turin and, Jun 16/26
      - as commander of the auxiliary forces of the Grand Alliance about the condition of the regiments, the preparations by the French, and the arrival of German and Imperial troops. 1. Great Britain. Army. 2. Grand Alliance, War of the, 1689-1697.
    - 10 ALS (in French) to William Blathwayt, Turin and the Camp at Scalingue, 1694 Jun 23/
      - Reporting the arrival of French, Jul 3-